ARNOL ROBLES T.

M

(+591) 67341446

arnol12157@gmail.com

Hi!

I have a degree in Systems Engineering, I like to learn new technologies, in the places where I worked I worked as a programmer and even as a lead, which allowed me to know in a better way all the pipeline necessary for the development of a videogame.

GAME DEVELOPER

SOME BEST PROJECTS













SKILLS

- Unity
- Easy AR
- Analytics
- PHP
- PlayFab
- Firebase
- MySQL
- **PostgreSQL**
- Oculus

WORK EXPERIENCE

GAMAGA - KONGREGATE - JAN. 2022 - PRESENT

SR. UNITY DEVELOPER

Development of mobile videogames, as well as a Lead Programmer for the coordination of tasks, planning and implementation of new features with Kongregate in the BitVerse project. Also colaborating on games like Animation Throwdown, Pocket Politics and TMNT: Mutant Madness

Technologies:

- Unity
- Firebase

Iron Source

- Kongregate SDK
- PlavFab •
- MADBRICKS PLAILABS MAY. 2023 AUG 2023

SR. UNITY DEVELOPER

Development and maintenance of the videogame Champions Ascension, collaborating with the tasks of new features as well as bug fixing, also coordinating tasks with the internal backend team of Plailabs.

Technologies:

- Unity
- TODOGAMES STUDIOS APR. 2016 DEC 2021

FOUNDER & LEAD PROGRAMMER

Development of videogames, mobile applications, AR and VR. Collaborating with the development, design and management of the projects created, thanks to some projects it was possible to capture the attention of the press and experts in the national and international area, winning several competitions and always learning something new.

Technologies:

- Unity
- PlayFab
- Photon
- PHP
- MySQL

- **Unity Analytics**
- Flutter
- Oculus
- EasyAR
- Arduino
- HEADLESS CHICKEN STUDIOS JUN. 2018 SEP. 2018

PROGRAMMER

Development of an "Advergame" for mobile devices for the company Sofía Ltda. The videogame consists of collecting different items along 3 different levels using any of the 3 available characters. There are 2 game modes, the first using simple buttons for movement and the second using the phone microphone to control the character's jump. All data and scores were saved on a PlayFab server.

Technologies:

- Unity
- PlayFab

ULTRACASAS.COM - JUL, 2017 - DEC, 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Maintaining the web portal, developing a new search engine with advanced filters and designing a new user experience, as well as generating statistics on the use of the platform for better data analysis.

Technologies:

- PHP
- Javascript
- MySQL

UNIVERSITY "UNIVALLE" - FEB. 2019 – JUN. 2022

TEACHER

Teacher and Tutor in the careers of "Videogame Technician" and "Systems Engineering" teaching the following subjects:

- Game Development
- Systems Project
- Emerging Technologies
- Artificial Intelligence for Videogames
- Videogames and Multimedia Workshop

BOLIVIAN CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY "SAN PABLO" - FEB. 2020 - JUN. 2022

TEACHER

Teacher in the career "Systems Engineering", teaching the following subject:

• Videogame Programming

NOTHING BOX STUDIOS - JUN. 2017 - DEC. 2018

PROGRAMMER

Collaborating with the development in different projects, especially in charge of the Artificial Intelligence area. Winner of the Eduardo Abaroa 2018 award in recognition of the best video game developed in Bolivia.

Technologies:

- Unity
- PlayFab

ENTEL S.A. - OCT. 2017 - NOV. 2017

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Developing a communication module between users and the company through Web Services using PHP as the main backend language, in order to implement it within the main platform of the Mobile Wallet.

Technologies:

PHP

NEOMIX LTDA. – JUN. 2016 – SEP. 2016

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Developing a purchasing and order management system for this company, which has modules for user access, purchase management, sales statistics, etc.

Technologies:

- Angular
- Node JS
- PostgreSQL

MINISTRY OF THE PRESIDENCE - "UPRE" – JUN. 2015 – NOV. 2015

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Providing support to the main platform of the Special Projects Unit "UPRE", which is responsible for the monitoring and control of the different works carried out by the ministry throughout the Bolivian territory.

Technologies:

- Yii Framework.
- MySQL.

EDUCATION

- DIPLOMA IN HIGHER EDUCATION UNIVERSITY MAJOR OF SAN ANDRÉS
- INSTITUTE GOLDEN BRIDGE
 ADVANCED ENGLISH AT TRAINING LEVEL

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SYSTEMS ENGINEERING MILITARY ENGINEERING SCHOOL

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

PLURINATIONAL EDUARDO ABAROA AWARD

MINISTRY OF CULTURE AND TOURISM

Winner of the award in 2017 and 2018 with the companies "Nothing Box Studios" and "TodoGames Studios" respectively.

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE CONFERENCE

GDG LA PAZ

Speaker with the topic "Artificial Intelligence for Videogames".

HACK DAY "VIDEOGAMES WITH VOICE RECOGNITION"

ORGANIZATION OF IBEROAMERICAN STATES "OEI"

1st place with the development of a videogame using voice languages in Aymara using the CMU Sphinx tool.

TECH ZONE

JALASOFT

Speaker "Special Guest" with the topic "First steps in a virtual world".

DEV FEST

GDG LA PAZ

Exhibitor and Speaker in 2016, 2017 and 2018.

BOLIVIA LAB

PUBLIC AND PRIVATE ENTITIES

Exhibitor at the videogame fair.

SPACE APP CHALLENGE

NASA

Semifinalist worldwide in the "People Choice Awards" category.

ONE CLICK JAM

ARGENTINA

2nd place with the development of a video game oriented to people with disabilities.

NOTHING JUSTIFY VIOLENCE EVENT

MINISTRY OF JUSTICE

2nd place with the development of a videogame against family abuse.

ACM ICPC

WORLWIDE EVENT

National and Latin American ranking in 2015, 2016 and 2017.

PUBLICATIONS

FIRST STEPS IN A VIRTUAL WORLD

JUNE 2017

Explaining the main aspects of Virtual Reality applied to videogames, technologies with which you can create a more immersive environment. Emphasizing that it is a tool for everyone and more people need to know about it.

A GAME INVITES YOU TO FEEL LIKE A PACIFIC WAR HERO

DECEMBER 2016

Describing how a historical event can be implemented in a video game so that all people who do not know or know very little about this event learn a little more by incorporating gamification in this type of knowledge.

VR IN BOLIVIA

JUNE 2016

Showing the development of VR applications, it also described the main components of an application and why it attracts the attention of experts. It was highlighted that TodoGames Studios is one of the first in the country to make use of this technology.

BOLIVIAN VIDEOGAME IS AMONG THE 25 BEST IN NASA CONTEST.

MAY 2016

Publication in the press where reference is made to the video game created for the NASA Space App Challenge, describing the most significant aspects of the project, highlighting points such as: the inclusion of professions within a virtual environment, a key aspect for the incorporation of physics and simulations within a real simulated environment.

TECHNOLOGY AGAINST VIOLENCE

MARCH 2015

Showing the development of a videogame for the Ministry of Justice, which is oriented to education about family abuse in the home. It was able to capture the attention of the local press, demonstrating how a videogame can influence people to behave well within their families.